妈咪 早安
Good morning, mom
早安 小宝贝
Good morning, puppy
今天才周三 对吧 杰
Hump day, am I right, Jay?
你2点半之后就自由了
Your day ends at 2:30
早死早超生
Can't come fast enough.
我指的是退休 杰 你说是不是
Quitting time. Am I right, jay?
我们不要把这点看得过重
Let's not make this a thing.
嘿 嘿 嘿 这是啥玩意儿
Whoa, whoa, whoa. What is this?
我的水煮蛋呢
Where's my soft-boiled egg?
我把它炒了
I scrambled it.
尝试一下新鲜事物对你有好处
It's good for you to try new things.
我才不要尝试新鲜事物呢
I don't want to try new things.
你不能突然对我这样
You can't just spring this on me.
曼尼 告诉你个坏消息
I have bad news, manny.
生活最刁难你的时候
This is not the biggest curve ball
还没到呢
that life is going to throw you.
哥们儿 不要拒绝新鲜事物
Buddy, don't close yourself off from new things.
我有没有跟你说过我对蟹肉饼的心路历程
I ever tell you the story about me and crab cakes?
恨之 试之 爱之
Thought I didn't like them, tried them, love them.
那电影版权也能这样吗
Are the movie rights available for that one?
邓菲家族春季例赛
Dunphy spring classic.
看下周谁来洗碗
Who's gonna do the dishes for the next week?
男孩大战女孩
Boys versus girls.
雄性激素大战雌性激素
Testosterone versus estrogen.
站着嘘嘘大战蹲着嘘嘘
Standing up to pee versus the squat.
-菲尔 快开始 -老爸
- Phil, come on! -Dad!
击球失误
Swing and a miss.
我摸清了她的路线 卢克
He's in her head, Luke.
男孩大获全胜 女生只有流口水的份
And boys rule and girls drool.
你才随时流口水
You drool all the time.
弄得老妈得带你去看专家
Mom had to take you to a specialist.
我还适应我的舌头呢
I'm still growing into my tongue.
妈 我能不能和罗宾去看电影
Hey, mom, can I go to the movies with robin?
不行 你还在关禁闭
No, you may not, 'cause you are still grounded.
那你能送我回房间吗
Then can I be sent to my room?
不行 我们在享受家庭的欢乐时光
No, 'cause we're having some fun family time.
我们整个美丽的下午都呆着外面
We're gonna spend this beautiful afternoon
享受新鲜空气 做点运动 好吧
outside in the fresh air, getting some exercise, okay?
快投 菲尔
Pitch it, Phil.
我勒个去
Oh, well.
游戏结束
That's the game.
什么意思 我们才刚刚开始
What do you mean? We just started.
那个是我们唯一的球
That was our only ball.
所以呢
So what?
游戏就这么结束了 就因为你怕
The game's over just because you're afraid
隔壁的傻蛋克里扎克先生吗
of stupid Mr. Kleezak?
对 我才不去他那里
Yep. I'm not going over there.
这比赛真有意思
That was fun.
如果汉尼拔或者弗雷德有孩子
If Hannibal Lecter and Freddy Krueger had a love child,
他也会害怕我们的隔壁邻居
he would be afraid of our next-door neighbor.
我通常不对别人做负面评价
I don't have a mean thing to say about anyone,
但是克里扎克先生的确
but Mr. Kleezak is...
不是个好人
not a nice person.
亲爱的 淡定点
Easy, honey.
-海莉 -米奇尔叔叔
- Hey, Haley. - Oh, hey, uncle Mitchell.
-你妈在吗 -不在
- Hey, is your mom home? - No.
她要带艾丽克斯去看肿瘤医生[谐音口误]
She had to take Alex to the oncologist.
天啊 怎么回事
Oh, my god, what's wrong?
她要配一副新眼镜
She needed new glasses.
-你是说验光师吧 -随便啦
- Oh. Did you mean optometrist? - Whatever.
-要给她带个话吗 -对对
- So, should I give her a message? - Yes, yes.
问她星期六晚上能不能帮忙
Could you ask her if she could possibly babysit
照看一下莉莉
Lily on Saturday night?
我们感激不尽
We'd really, really appreciate it.
星期六晚上我们要和
Saturday night, we're having dinner
胡焦 朗吉奴斯以及克里斯宾吃饭
with pepper, longinus, and crispin.
他们都是同志
They're our gay friends.
我觉得大家都知道
I think that was clear.
我最近大部分时间都跟
I've been spending a lot of time
异性恋的人呆在一起
with a lot of straight people lately.
亲爱的 我需要跟我的伙计们好好玩一晚
And, darling, I need a night with my homies.
-你是说你的同性闺蜜吧 -对
- You mean homos. - Okay. Yeah.
或许你留下来照看莉莉会更好
You know what? Maybe you should stay in and babysit.
我们的保姆不能来
Yeah, our babysitter bailed,
我们有点小麻烦
and we're kind of in a bind, so --
我能行 我能照看莉莉
I can do it. I can watch lily.
我很在行的 我现在就在照看卢克呢
I'm really good. I'm babysitting Luke right now.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
你想照看莉莉
You want -- you want to babysit lily?
亲爱的 真的很感谢
Oh, well, that's very sweet, honey,
但是你是个很受欢迎的女孩子
but you're -- you're a very popular girl.
我想你有更好的事情做
I'm sure you have better things to do, so --
真的 我现在很闲
Oh, seriously, I'm totally free.
现代被关禁闭可比古时候糟糕多了
Being grounded is so much worse than it was in the olden days.
我朋友不断给我发短信 更新facebook
My friends text and facebook
谈论他们各种有意思的事情
all the fun stuff they're doing
我却只能呆在家里和老爹玩搭积木
while I'm stuck at home playing jenga with my dad.
你说真的吗
Are you serious?
你甚至可以不给我钱
You don't even have to pay me.
我发誓把她照顾得妥妥的
I promise I'll take super good care of her.
好吧 如此甚好 谢谢了
Okay, well, that would be great. Thank you.
好的 星期六见
Yes, well, we'll see you on Saturday night.
-拜拜 亲爱的 -拜
- Bye, sweetie. - Bye.
卢克
Luke?
你在想些什么
What are you thinking?!
海莉是一个甜美时尚的女孩
Haley is a very sweet and fashionable girl,
但显然不是一个合格的保姆
but seems hardly a responsible caregiver!
我们需要一名临时看孩子的人
Well, you know what? We needed a sitter.
她是我们的家人
She's family.
我们就让她试一次吧
I say we give her a shot.
试一次 用我们的孩子
A shot? Oh, with our only child?
当然 为什么不呢
Sure, why not?
如果有什么差错的话
If something goes wrong,
我们只需回到东方 再领养一个
We'll just pop over to the orient and grab another one.
什么
What?
我是卢克·邓菲 我住在隔壁
My name is Luke Dunphy. I live next door.
你有什么事
What do you want?
我想到你的院子里把球拿回来
I want to get our ball from your yard.
我可不想让你把后面搞得一团糟
I don't want you messing around back there.
回家去吧
Just go home.
你要去潜水吗
Are you going scuba diving?
你为什么要带着个罐子
Why do you have that tank?
你聪明吗
You being smart?
你是说在学校吗 还行
You mean in school? Well, I do okay.
老师说我容易走神
My teacher says I get distracted.
为什么你的鼻子里会有管子
Why do you have that tube in your nose?
好玩
For fun.
真的吗 我能试试吗
Really? Can I try?
这是氧气
It's oxygen.
我们房子里也有
We have that in our house,
但我们不需要用罐子装
but we don't need tanks.
看在上帝的份上 去拿你的球吧
Oh, for god's sake, just get your ball.
好的
Okay.
我的天啊
Oh my god.
我在看新闻
I was watching the news,
又有一群鸟从天空掉下来死了
and another flock of birds fell out of the sky dead.
发生什么事了
What is happening?
亲爱的 你不能再看新闻了
Sweetie, you got to stop watching the news.
这就是你的解决办法 拥抱无知吗
That's your big solution -- embrace ignorance?
你们两个在争辩什么
What are you two arguing about?
算了 我不想知道
Never mind, I don't want to know.
我去去就回
Be back in a couple hours.
你要去哪
Whoa, whoa, whoa, where you going?
去我朋友沃特家看《正午迷情》
To my friend Walt's house to watch "High noon."
我喜欢西部电影 越血腥越好
Ooh, I love westerns -- the bloodier, the better.
这是我最喜欢的影片类型
that's my favorite type of movie --
这个和任何以啦啦队竞争为背景的电影
That and anything set against the backdrop
都是我的最爱
of competitive cheerleading.
沃特是那个总是在玩滑板的那个人吗
Is Walt the one who's always skateboarding?
不是 玩那个他的氧气瓶要放哪里
No. Where would he put his oxygen tank?
好的 我真迷糊了
Okay, now I'm really confused.
你的口气和沃特像极了
You sound like Walt.
他也经常犯迷糊 这可真是太搞笑了
He gets confused a lot. It's hilarious.
等等 你说的是克里扎克先生吗
Wait, are we talking about Mr. Kleezak?
是的 我到他的住所去拿回我的球
Yeah. I went over to his house to get my ball,
然后我们就开始一起玩耍了
and we've been hanging out.
你去过克里扎克先生的家吗
You were in Mr. Kleezak's house?
卢克 这可不行
Luke, that is not okay.
为什么
Why not?
他人真的很好很有趣
He's really nice and funny.
听听这个笑话
Listen to this joke.
好的 两个德国鬼子走进一家酒吧
Okay, two krauts walk into a bar.
菲尔 这可不妙
Phil, this is not good.
亲爱的 别那么武断
Honey, don't jump to conclusions.
让他讲完这个笑话
Let him finish the joke.
有一个是个跛子
And one of them has a limp.
你不能再去那个人的家里
You may not go back to that man's house.
-为什么 -因为 他是个怪人
- Why not? - Because...he's weird.
-而且他不是个好人 -对
- And not very nice. - Yeah.
你们也是这么说我的朋友奥利弗的
That's what you said about my friend Oliver.
奥利弗
Oliver.
是那个差点把我们车库烧没的人吗
Oliver who almost burned down our garage?
他喜欢熔化东西
He likes to melt stuff.
说得好像你自己很完美似的
Like you're so perfect.
卢克 对不起 但是你妈妈和我
Luke, I'm sorry, but your mother and I
对此不是很安心
just aren't comfortable with this.
这不公平
That's so unfair.
你们甚至都不了解他
You don't even know him
因为你们害怕跟他说话
'cause you're two afraid to talk to him.
兄弟 我们只是关心你
Buddy, we're just looking out for you.
你们从来都不喜欢我的朋友
You never like any of my friends.
我们这么做是对的
We're doing the right thing.
绝对没错
Absolutely.
是吗
Aren't we?
我不知道 我是说 他说的有道理
I don't know. I mean, he makes a point.
我们不了解那个男人
We don't know the man,
小孩能和老人成为朋友 对吧
and little kids can be friends with old people, right?
当然可以 这有很多例子
Of course they can. There's tons of examples.
《飞屋环游记》 《老爷车》 《大地惊雷》
"Up," Um, "Gran torino," "True grit."
卡通 自杀 她失去了一条手臂[对应菲尔讲的三部电影情节]
Cartoon, kills himself, she loses an arm.
我们得跟那个人谈谈
We've got to go talk to that guy.
-现在 -是的
- Now? - Yeah.
现在很黑了
It's so dark.
好的 号码就在电话旁边
Okay, so, the numbers are by the phone.
冰箱里有吃的
There's food in the fridge.
我刚给她换了尿布 你要做的就是
I just changed her diaper, so all you need to do
半小时后把她放下来
is put her down in about a half-hour
而且决不允许连环杀手靠近门前一步
And not let a serial killer in the front door.
如果他很帅怎么办
Well, what if he's cute?
那就把他留给我们
Then save him for us.
不准人进 不准人出
Nobody in, nobody out.
我们会没事的
Oh, we're gonna be totally fine.
你们去开始你们的同志活动吧
You just go get your gay on.
我们已经像大金刚那样充满活力了
Oh, it is on like Donkey Kong.
很明显还没开始 但是马上就要开始了
Well, clearly it's not on yet, but it will be.
谢谢 好的 快点 我们走
Thanks. So, okay, come on. Let's go.
我告诉你 孩子
I'm telling you, kid,
这将是一场你永世难忘的音乐会
This is a concert you're never gonna forget.
世界上最棒的音乐
Greatest music in the world.
等等 这是什么
Wait a minute. What's this?
怎么了
What do you mean?
我们要去看什么
What are we seeing?
交响乐《四季》
The symphony "The four seasons."
我以为是法兰基·维里和他的四季合唱团
I thought we were seeing Frankie Valli and the Four Seasons.
不是的 这是维瓦尔第的《四季》
No. No, it's Vivaldi.
除了乐器什么都没有了 这不是坑爹吗
Oh, crap. You mean nothing but instruments?
-我可不要进去 -不行 你必须进去
- I'm out of here. - No, you're not out. You're in.
我讨厌这类音乐
I hate this kind of music.
杰 你总是这样
Jay, you always do that.
每次我们想要尝试新花样
Every time we try something new,
你第一反应总是反对
Your first reaction is always no.
因为我已经久经世事
It's 'cause I'm old enough
知道自己喜欢的是什么
to know what I like and what I don't like.
那关于蟹肉饼的心路历程呢
What about the crab cakes?
那只是一个意外
That was a fluke.
我总不能在那无聊的音乐涂上调味酱
And I can't slather that boring music in tartar sauce.
这么说来 我就要尝试新花样
So I have to try new things,
就像炒鸡蛋 可你却不用
Like scrambled eggs, but you don't have to?
看看你都做了什么
You see what you're doing?
你正在让这个家庭支离破碎
You're tearing this family apart.
别说这个了 你们进去
Let's take it down a notch. You two go in.
玩的开心点 我们待会见
Have a great time. I'll see you later.
那你准备去干嘛
What are you going to do?
行如男子汉 快如闪电
I'm gonna walk like a man, fast as I can,
直奔对面那家酒吧
To that bar over there.
如果你们是法兰基·维里的粉丝
And if you knew Frankie Valli,
听到刚那句话你们老早心潮澎湃了
You'd be cracking up right now.
别管他
It's okay.
我和你们说 约翰·施耐得就是那么独一无二
I'm telling you, John Schneider was the one!
那个《赫扎德的杜克斯》里面的约翰·施耐得
John schneider, from "The dukes of hazzard"?
那就是你首次来电
That was your first crush?
现在一想波·杜克就口水直流
Oh, my god, yes. Bo Duke -- delicious.
他饰演一个乡巴佬驾驶的一辆被称为李将军的车
He was a redneck who drove a car called the general lee
上面还印着一面美国南方联邦旗
With a giant confederate flag on it.
看着难道不会让你性趣骤降
That wasn't a turn-off for you?
听着 我知道这听起来很蠢
Look, I know it was all kinds of wrong,
可是哥就是好这口
But the heart wants what the heart wants.
理查·基尔 想想就性奋
Richard Gere. Oh, my god.
我可是个军官 可不懂绅士之礼
I'll be the officer. Don't be a gentleman.
蒙哥马利·克利夫特
Montgomery Clift.
那是谁
Who?
别装了 克里斯宾 你又没这么嫩
Don't do that, Crispin. You're not that young.
不管怎么说 我的初电是个同志 至少我尝试过
Anyway, my crush was gay. At least I had a shot.
你和蒙哥马利·克利夫特来过 你究竟多大了
You had a shot with Montgomery Clift? How old are you?
我要把你开膛破肚 就像你从没在世上存在过
I will cut you like it was nothing, farm boy.
听听 我真怀念这种感觉
Oh, see, I miss this.
你呢 米奇尔
Wait. What about you, Mitchell?
好吧 我但是并不知道这是否算来电
Um, okay, well, I-I didn't know it was a crush
因为那是我才8岁
Because I was only 8 at the time.
我8岁时什么都懂了
I knew when I was 8.
你八岁时 是个人都懂了
Everyone knew when you were 8.
朗吉奴斯 起来 我要和你换位置
Longinus, get up. We're switching seats.
好了 我来继续说
Okay, okay, back to me, back to me, back to me.
我当时刚看好《七个毕业生》
So, I had just seen "St. Elmo's fire," And --
米奇尔 快看 那是你父亲
Oh, Mitchell, look, it's your father.
那是你父亲 秀色可餐嘛
Ooh. That's your father? He's cute.
你能别这么性趣昂然吗
Okay, can you please turn it off for one second?
看他只身前来 何不请来合坐
Ooh, he's all alone. Invite him over.
可不能这么做
Yeah, that's not something we're gonna do.
别紧张 你早就出柜了
Relax, your dad knows you're gay.
可他不知道我能做到这地步
He doesn't know I'm this gay.
这让我们情何以堪
Excuse us?
普里契特先生
Oh, Mr. Pritchett!
杰 杰 这里这里
Jay! Jay! Yoo-hoo!
他真像你在湖边搞上的那个牙医
Oh, he looks like that dentist you hooked up with in laguna.
对 我可是有恋父情结的
Oh, yeah, yeah. That was in my daddy phase.
继续吧 继续开我玩笑吧
Yes, please, keep this up. This is fun for me.
-小伙子们 你们好 -你好啊 老爸
- Fellas, how you doing? - Hey, dad.
-你好 杰 -你好啊 亲爹
- Hi, jay. - Hello, daddy.
你在这干嘛
What are you doing here?
我乘歌洛莉亚和曼尼看演出的时候 来这里喝一杯
I'm just getting a drink while Gloria and Manny see a show.
-和我们一起吧 -算了 我不想打扰你们雅兴
- Well, please join us. - No, I don't want to intrude.
-他不想打扰我们的雅兴 -你哪有打扰我们
- He doesn't want to intrude. - You are not intruding.
我只是想在酒吧里看场比赛
I'm just gonna watch the game at the bar.
他只是想在酒吧里看场比赛
He just wants to watch the game at the bar, so...
坐下吧 我们最多还有25分钟就走了
Oh, sit down. We're up by 25 with a minute to go.
好吧 那我就坐一会吧
Well, maybe just for a minute.
好吧
Okay.
一般男人围在一起喝酒都做些什么
So, what does a guy got to do to get a drink around here?
就这么干坐着
Nobody say anything.
贾斯汀 再来点酒
Justin, more booze.
米奇尔刚刚想告诉我们
Oh, Mitchell was just about to tell us
第一个和他来电的男人是谁
Who his first boy crush was.
-我可没有要说 -让我来帮你了解下前情
- No, no, I wasn't. - Let me bring you up to speed.
克里斯宾的那位是乔伊·麦金太尔
Crispin's was Joey Mcintyre,
不知道为何人
whoever that is.
朗吉奴斯说他的那位是约翰·施耐得
Longinus said John Schneider.
你叫朗吉奴斯
Your name is Longinus?
我知道 但我从来没机会被感化
I know. I never stood a chance.
小卡迷恋于理查·基尔
Cam's was Richard Gere,
而我则钟情于蒙哥马利·克利夫特
and I was Monty Clift.
至少你那位本来就是个同志
Well, at least yours was gay.
我是说 你可能有机会发展一下
I mean, you might've had a shot.
谢谢
Thank you.
克里斯宾 站起来 我要坐他旁边
Crispin, up. I'm sitting next to this one.
欢迎
Welcome.
他就在那
He's right there.
好了
All right.
-克里扎克先生 -克里扎克先生
- Mr. Kleezak? - Mr. Kleezak?
门是开着的
It's open.
亲爱的 他没动静 他还好吗
Honey, he's not moving. Is he okay?
要知道答案只有一种办法
Well, there's only one way to find out.
克里扎克先生
Mr. Kleezak?
好吧
Okay, look.
不知道他还有没有没呼吸
I don't know if he's breathing.
他还有脉搏吗
Does he have a pulse?
要知道答案只有一种办法
Well, there's only one way to find out.
不要再推我了 你来
Would you stop pushing me? You do it.
我讨厌这样
I hate this.
我要把卢克宰了
I'm gonna kill Luke.
天啊 他是冰冷的
Oh, my god. He's ice-cold.
天啊
Oh, my god! Ugh!
对不起 我们以为你出事了
I'm sorry. We thought there was something wrong with you.
-对不起 -什么
- Sorry. - What?!
我们以为你出事了
We thought there was something wrong with you!
菲尔
Phil.
你好
Hi.
我们还没有正式认识 我是菲尔·邓菲
We haven't, uh, formally met. Phil Dunphy.
对 我认识你
Yeah, I know you.
你私闯我家 还乱摸我
You're the guy who just broke into my house and fondled me.
不 我们很担心 以为你死了
No. No. We were just concerned that you looked dead.
无意冒犯
No offense.
你们在这干什么
Well, what are you doing here?
我们的孩子卢克告诉我们
Oh, um, our son, Luke, told us
你请他到你家看电影
that you invited him over here to watch movies,
你应该可以理解
and I'm sure you could understand
我们担心这件事的理由
why we would... be concerned about that.
-不理解 -菲尔
- No. - Phil.
-你做得好极了 -宝贝
- You're doing great. - Honey.
等下 你的意思是 我是变态吗
Wait, are you saying that I'm some kind of pervert?
-不 -可能 不是
- No. - Probably...not.
我没有让他过来
Look, I didn't ask him to come over here.
各人自扫门前雪 莫管他人瓦上霜
I was minding my own business, like you should be.
好
Okay.
说句公道话 孩子的事就是我们的事
But in all fairness, our son is our business.
很好 那就好好看住他
Well, then, keep him.
也让你女儿不要再开车撞我的垃圾箱了
And keep your daughter from driving into my garbage cans.
我
I --
你跳性感舞的时候
And keep your blinds closed
拜托你拉上百叶窗
when you're doing your little sexy dance.
天啊 他看到我的性感舞了
Oh, god, he's seen my sexy dance.
我十二岁时
So I'm 12 years old
在我好朋友吉姆家过夜
I was staying over night at my best friend Jim's house,
我们两个都不想睡觉
And neither one of us want to go to sleep.
我知道接下来是什么
I know where this is going.
克里斯宾 你不至于想歪吧
You're better than that, Crispin.
我们就偷偷溜出去看电影
So, we sneak off to the movies,
我们看的这部片子叫《所罗门王》
And we see this little picture called "Solomon and Sheba."
里面的示巴女王是
And Sheba was...
-吉娜·劳洛勃丽吉达 -答对了
- Gina Lollobrigida! - Bingo!
我发誓 我这一辈子总有一天
And for the rest of my life, I swore, one day,
我要和吉娜·劳洛勃丽吉达结婚
I would marry Gina Lollobrigida.
老爸 你差不多算是做到了
Well, dad, you kind of did.
我知道
I hear that!
这很不错 里面有什么
Mmm. These are good. What's in them?
玛格丽特加苦艾酒
It's a Margarita with a shot of absinthe.
苦艾酒可以加深感情
Absinthe makes the heart grow fonder.
你是在说双关语还是口齿不清啊
Ohh, are you making a bad pun or just lisping?
真不敢相信 我白开这么长的路
I can't believe I drove all the way to the valley
到山谷里去接你
to pick you up.
贾斯汀 加酒
Justin, more booze!
海莉 一切都还好吗
Haley, hi. Is -- is everything okay?
是的 怎么了
Yeah, why?
我刚看见一个男人走过客厅
Because I just saw a man walk through the living room.
什么 你在哪
What? Where are you?
我可以通过电脑上的摄像头看到
I can see through the camera on the computer.
你竟然监视我 天啊
You're spying on me? Oh, my god.
天啊 这也太逊了吧
Oh, my god. That is so lame.
我不知道你看到了什么
Look, I don't know what you think you saw
或许是电视 或许是反射的影像
Maybe the TV, or the reflection,
或许你觉得我的身材看起来像男孩
or maybe you think that my body's just shaped like a boy,
就像我没有臀部什么的
like I don't have hips or something.
不 你的身材好极了
No, no, no, no. You have a-a darling figure.
我只是担心
I was just concerned that
太伤人了
That hurts so much.
这种事情我以为只有我老妈会做
This is the kind of thing that I expect from my mother,
没想到我这么酷的叔叔也这么干
but not from my cool uncle,
谢谢你这样的信任
so thank you for all of your trust.
好了 对不起
Okay, I'm -- sorry. Sorry.
难以置信
Unbelievable.
你得走了
You got to go.
好吧
Okay.
好
Yeah. All right.
谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
爸爸 我从来没听过你唱歌
Dad, I've never seen you sing before.
那是因为你没看过我洗澡
Well, you never saw me in the shower.
我可没要邀请你们跟我一起洗啊
And don't anybody go there.
我十二岁那年
When I was 12 years old,
我爸走进我的房间 逮到我在做
My father walked into my bedroom and caught me doing
一个男生所能做出的最丢脸的事
the most embarrassing thing that a boy can do --
在跳麦当娜的《幸运星》
Dancing to Madonna's "Lucky star."
从那一刻开始
And from that moment on,
我就开始对他隐藏我内心的某一部分
There's always been a part of me that I've kept from him.
然而 现在的他
And yet, yeah, here he was,
在跟我的朋友谈笑风声
You know, laughing with my friends.
我说不准
And...I don't know.
也许问题出在我
Maybe the problem was me.
罗伯·劳
Rob Lowe.
-在哪 -在哪 -在哪 -在哪
- Where? - Where? - Where? - Where?
不不 《七个毕业生》中的罗伯·劳
No, no, Rob Lowe from "St. Elmo's fire."
这是我以前的来电对象 我爱他
That was -- that was my crush. I loved him.
我了解 他当时可是个帅小伙
I get that. He was a good-looking kid.
-当真 -当然
- Right? - Yeah.
《行如男子汉》
Hey, "Walk like a man"?
我会唱 但我走起路来可不像男子汉
Well, I can sing it, but I can't do it.
我刚刚似乎把什么弄伤了
I think I just broken somthing.
-痛 -护士
- Ow! - Nurse!
喂
Hello?
求您告诉我我的鞋在你那
Please tell me that you have my shoes.
为什么你的鞋在我这
Why would I have your shoes?
因为我昨晚把他们留在你舅舅家了
Because I left them at your uncles's house last night.
什么 你怎么没穿鞋就走了
What? How could you leave without your shoes?
我经常不穿鞋子到处走
I go a lot of places without shoes.
我现在就没有穿
I'm not wearing shoes right now.
不 等等
Oh, wait.
那是因为我把它们落在你舅舅家了
That's 'cause I left them at your uncles's house.
这可惨了
This is a disaster!
也许他们会以为那双鞋是他们自己的
Well, maybe they'll think they're theirs.
他们是同志 他们对他们的鞋了如指掌
They're gay. They know what shoes they own.
多谢 沃特
Thanks a lot, Walt.
你就不能对我父母友善一次吗
You couldn't be nice to my parents for two seconds,
弄得现在我被禁止跟你玩了
so now I'm not allowed to hang out with you.
你要我怎么样
What do you want from me?
我以为你是我朋友
I thought you were my friend.
你答应过我教我怎么种番茄
You promised to teach me how to grow tomatoes,
还有带我去喝蛋奶乳的
and you were gonna take me for an egg cream.
算了吧 你就一小屁孩
Forget it. You're a little kid.
你别跟我用激将法
I don't need the aggravation.
这样 对不起我"激怒"你了
Oh, sorry I "Aggravated" You.
随便告诉一下 一堆人觉得我可爱死了
And, just so you know, a lot of people think I'm adorable.
我打不开
I can't open this.
也许你去音乐会就不用
Maybe if you had gone to the concert instead --
你帮我打开好吗
Could you open it, please?
我可以 但我年纪已经大到知道
I would, but I'm old enough to know
我不喜欢打开阿司匹林瓶子
that I don't like opening aspirin bottles.
喂
Hello?
-爸 -你们是怎么做到了
- Hey, Dad! - How do you guys do it?
我醉得叫警察跟我一起喝
I thought cops could drink.
我只是 我想告诉你说
Listen, I just -- I wanted to say
我昨晚和你玩得很开心
I had such a good time with you last night,
-我想要 -等下 我有电话进来
- and I wanted to -- -hey, hold on. I got call waiting. Yeah.
喂
Yeah?
看来不爱早起 了解了
Woof, not a morning person. Good to know.
我还有五公里就到
Listen, I'm five away.
但愿你喜欢蓝莓烤饼和达斯汀·斯普林菲尔德
I hope you like Blueberry Scones and Dusty Springfield.
-你是哪位 -胡焦 小傻帽
- Who is this? - Pepper, silly.
今天的沙漠那估计热翻天
It's gonna be a scorcher in the desert today,
相应地少穿点
So dress accordingly.
到你家那条街了 待会见
Oh, this is your street. See you in a minute.
这下麻烦大了
Holy crap!
你那个朋友 叫胡焦那个
That friend of yours, that Pepper.
他正在来我家的路上 为什么
He's on his way over here. Why?
昨晚你跟他约好的 你不记得了
Well, you made a date with him last night. Don't you remember?
如果我跟个男人有约 我肯定我记得
I think I would remember if I made a date with a guy!
我跟你讲 我认识棕榈泉的一个家伙
I'm telling you, I know a guy in Palm Springs
他有人类所知的所有年份的古董唱片
Who has every single Vintage record known to man.
我明天开车过去 一起去吧
I'm driving out there tomorrow. Come with me.
这可是个约会
It's a date!
是的
All right!
我当时醉了
I was drunk.
我可不要跟沙漠女王普里西拉去购物
I'm not going shopping with Priscilla, queen of the desert.
好的 爸
Okay, Dad.
我对我们目前的关系很满意
Well, I'm feeling really good about our relationship,
而我也想要保持这种状态更长久一些
and I want to hold on to that for a little while longer,
所以我现在要行动了 再聊 挂了
so I'm gonna go ahead and hang up with you.
替我大大地亲下胡焦
Give pepper a big kiss for me.
歌洛莉亚 现在听我说
Gloria, now, listen.
我知道音乐会那事让你很不爽
I know that you're upset with me about that concert thing,
你有权这样 但现在你要帮我
And rightfully so, but you have to help me.
怎么办
What is it?
似乎我跟米奇尔的朋友胡焦有约
It seems I made plans with Mitchell's friend Pepper.
这是个人名吗 叫胡椒
That's someone's name? Pepper?
是的 这只是冰山一角
Yes, and that's just the tip of the iceberg.
还有个家伙叫朗吉奴斯[圣徒]
There's another guy named Longinus.
但胡焦这会就回到我们家
But Pepper's gonna be here any second.
他要带我去棕榈泉
He's gonna take me to Palm Springs
去买唱片
To go shopping for records.
待会他到我们这
Now, when he gets here,
你可不可以假装我们这有急事要处理
Can you pretend there's some kind of an emergency?
可以吗 求你了
Can you do that, please?
疼 杰
Iay, Jay!
恐怕你得赶紧送我去医院
I-I think you'll have to take me now to the hospital.
我现在头痛欲裂
My head is in pain.
-你是说像这样吧 -正是 多谢
- Do you mean like that? - Yes, thank you.
好嘞 好戏登场了
Okay, it's showtime.
这种语境下 这话就是指演戏
And with this guy, I mean that literally.
我来也
I'm here!
我的神呐
Oh, my god.
你们这个家真是无可挑剔
What I could do with this house.
你好啊 杰
Hello, Jay.
抓紧时间 这一趟车程有两小时呢
Chop, chop -- it's a two-hour drive,
还不算上折扣商场那一站
Not counting our stop at the outlet mall.
好吧 歌洛莉亚 我们要走了
Oh, okay. Um, Gloria, we're leaving!
你好 您就是胡焦吧
Hello. You must be Pepper.
哎哟喂
Ay, ay, ay.
-我的头啊 -你没事吧 歌洛莉亚
- My head. - What's the matter, Gloria?
哦 没事
Oh, nothing.
刚吃点冰淇淋
I just had a little ice cream. Huh?
他一天到晚喋喋不休 都在讲你
He hasn't stopped talking about you all day long.
嫂夫人真是魅力摄人
You are stunning.
有妻如此 夫复何求
How rich are you?
你真的没事吗 歌洛莉亚
Are you sure you're all right, gloria?
我好着呢 [西语]亲爱的
I feel great, mi amor.
他能和你出去我真开心
I am so happy that he's doing this with you,
因为任我想方设法 他还是顽固不化
because I never get him to do anything different,
听一场维瓦尔第都不肯
Like the Vivaldi, hmm?
比起我来 他好像更喜欢你哦
I think he likes you more than me.
你们两个玩得开心点
You two have a great time together.
好吧 但我们得早点回来
All right, but we got to be back early,
我还有事要做 你懂的
Because, you know, I got that work thing.
那些事我都推掉了 没什么要你忙的
No, no, I canceled everything. You don't have anything.
你可以和他玩上一整天
You can spend all day long with him.
太棒了 那咱出发吧
Wonderful. Well, shall we?
天啊 塔卢拉
Oh, my god. Tallulah! Oh!
别担心 等你一抱她 就不叫了
Don't worry. She'll stop yapping when she gets on your lap.
艾丽克斯 快点 就要迟到了
Alex, honey, come on. We're gonna be late.
近期有一群牛无故倒毙
A herd of cows dropped dead for no reason.
地球很危险 我哪也不去
I'm not going anywhere.
觉醒吧 无知愚民
Get your affairs in order, people.
世界末日来了
This is the end.
别逗了
Don't be ridiculous.
外面才没什么好怕的呢
There's nothing out there to be afraid of.
克里扎克先生
Mr. Kleezak.
我可不习惯被人捅醒
I'm not used to waking up with people poking me.
可把我吓坏了
I was startled, you know.
那件事真不好意思
We're really sorry about that.
那什么...
Yeah, well...
这是我自己种的洋葱
These are onions from my garden.
哇 太谢谢您了
Wow. Thank you so much.
您人真好
That is so nice.
这些溢美之辞还是省省吧
Yeah, well, don't go throwing any parades.
不就是洋葱吗
They're onions.
我以前当过消防员
I used to be a fireman, you know.
我从不伤害孩子
I don't hurt kids.
您要进来坐吗
Sir, would you like to come in?
跟孩子说一声 今天三点开播《原野奇侠》
Just tell the boy that "Shane" is on today at 3:00.
他该看看
He should watch it.
您不妨亲自告诉他
Maybe you could tell him yourself.
他就在楼上 等一下啊
He's -- he's right upstairs. Hang on.
卢克 宝贝 快下来
Luke, honey, come on down!
你的朋友 沃特来了
Your friend...Walt is here.
-您真的太好了 -是啊
- This is just so sweet. - Yeah.
只要你别跳舞 什么都好说
Well, just don't start dancing.
人们总会出乎你的意料
People can surprise you.
你为表象所蒙蔽 看惯了他们人前的一面
You get used to thinking of them one way, stuck in their roles.
以为眼见为实
They are what they are.
我年轻那会...
I was young at the time...
这时他们就会出其不意
And then they do something that shows you
展示出自己深藏不露
there's all this depth and dimension
不为你所知的复杂内心
that you never knew existed.
你是在说罗伯·劳吗
Are you talking about Rob Lowe?
我只是说他是演艺界全才
I'm just saying he's a very versatile actor.
我觉得英俊长相实际上限制了他的发展
I think his good looks have actually held him back.
这点我同意
Well, I can relate to that.
-海莉 -我们得谈谈
- Haley! - We need to talk.
我知道昨晚的事把你们吓得不轻
I know I freaked out on you last night,
但你们也得站在我的角度想想啊
but you have to see it from my point of view.
-你们一直在监视我 -没错
- You were totally spying on me. - I know.
你侵犯了第一修正案赋予我的隐私权
You were invading my first-amendment right to privacy.
正是
We were.
我受够了别人的猜疑
I'm sick and tired of people not trusting me.
-我理解 -尤其是你们
- I get it. - And especially you guys.
我没把你们当老派长辈
I don't think of you guys as my uncles,
我一直当你们是知心朋友
I think of you as my friends.
要是连朋友的信任都失去了
And if your friends don't believe in you,
你还能留下些什么
then what else do you have?
迪兰的鞋子算不算
Dylan's shoes?
千万别告诉我妈
Please don't tell my mom.
开车回去记得系安全带哦
Buckle up.